Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
OK. kid. out loud now.
so as I can hear you.
I'm checkin' the passengers.
front and back.
Shuttin' the doors. Rear section first.
Then the front section.
And the doors are closed. I'm checkin'
indicators to make sure doors are locked.
I remove my key. go back out the window
to make sure no one's bein' dragged.
51st Street next stop.
Next stop. 51st Street.
How'd I do?
Now you take my advice. kid.
You serve your six months. and
then you put in for the motorman.
Watch it now. we're comin' in.
- 59th Street.
- No. it ain't.
51st Street.
Sorry. this station is 51st Street.
Never say you're sorry.
Someone may come back here
and hit you in your damn nose!
Grand Central Station next stop.
Next stop. Grand Central.
If I was you I'd start studyin' for
that motorman exam right now.
Tell you the truth. Mr Mattson.
I have been.
Every car in the IRT is 72 feet long.
Costs $ 150.000. weighs 75.000Ibs.
This is where I get off. You're doin' fine.
Yeah. I'll see ya.
Hey. what's the rush. chief?
We ain't gonna leave without ya!
33rd Street next stop. Next stop is 33rd.
What's wrong. dude?
Ain't you never seen a sunset before?
Hey! How am I supposed
to see with you...?
- Holy God! What do you want?
- I'm taking your train.
You're takin' my train?
Hey!
Turn around.
I got s-s-somethin' to show ya.
- What's goin' on?
- Shut up!
I won't tell you again. Open the door
or I'll blow your head off.
May I get by. please?
No. you don't wanna go in there.
Suppose I do anyway?
Then I'll shoot your pee-pee off.
Now just go back out the window
and tell me what you see.
Someone leanin' against the head car.
The second he comes aboard.
you sh-sh-shut the doors.
Keep your hand off
the microphone. buddy.
- All right. Mr Green?
- 100 per cent. Mr Blue.
Get moving. will you?
Oh!
Shelley. give that to the meathead
upstairs. will ya?
Right this way. Just follow me.
Shelley. have you seen
Lieutenant Garber?
Oh! Lieutenant. it's so nice of you
to leave your duties long enough
to escort our distinguished
guests around the facilities.
May I present to you Mr Yashimura.
Mr Matsumoto.
Mr Tomashita.
And Mr Naka... Nakabashi?
These gentlemen are all directors of
the Tokyo Metropolitan Subway System.
Gentlemen. I'd like you to meet
Lieutenant Zachary Garber
of our own New York
Transit Authority Police.
A pleasure. gentlemen.
When you're finished. send them up to 13.
The chairman would like to say
goodbye to them personally.
Sayonara!
Follow me. gentlemen. New York City
Subway is the largest in the world.
with 237 miles of track. 7.000...
Gentlemen. please. New York City
Subway is the largest in the world.
7.000 cars. 237 miles of track...
- Say "when". Mr Blue.
- You just keep going. will you?
You're still in switchin'. Why don't you
peg it up? You're green all the way.
We're in no hurry. Atchoo!
Your cold sounds pretty bad.
I woke up in the middle
of the night with it.
- What happened?
- Must've bucked.
You told me you could drive this thing.
It's the train. She bucks
all the time. She's a dog.
This is the headquarters
of the Transit Police.
which occupies the entire
second floor of this building.
We call it the nerve centre.
The status board pinpoints the disposition
of every Transit Authority patrolman
presently in the field.
That's it. Get a good shot of that.
Things are usually jumpin'
pretty good in here.
I suppose you gentlemen have your share
of crime in the Tokyo subways. right?
Right? Well. that's the way it goes.
These are the assignment desks. One
for each of the lines: the BMT. the IRT.
the IND.
There's our artist in residence.
And right through here is our operations
lieutenant. Mr Rico Patrone.
who. on weekends. works for the Mafia.
Rico. I'd like you to meet some
good friends of the chairman.
- Hiya.
- Very good friends. Rico.
Hiya.
Rico. these are the directors
of the Tokyo subway.
Tell us about some of the excitin' things
that have happened in the New York City
Subway System lately. Rico.
Well. we had a bomb scare
in the Bronx yesterday.
But it turned out to be a cantaloupe.
I'm busy. Zach. OK?
In the course of a normal week.
the average TA policeman deals with
such crimes as robbery. assault.
murder. drunkenness.
illness. vandalism.
mishegaas.
abusiveness. sexual molestation.
exhibitionism...
- What's your name. motorman?
- Denny Doyle. sir.
- Ever been written up?
- Once.
- What for?
- Runnin' a red signal. How about you?
Twice. Once on the Canarsie...
That's right. Mr Green. Tell Mr Doyle
all about yourself. will you?
OK. Stop it about here.
I'm takin' your brake handle
and the reverse key. Denny.
Atchoo!
I want your cuttin' key also.
That's it.
You'll hear from Command Centre
in a minute or two.
You will ignore the call.
Is that clear. Mr Doyle?
Yes. sir. They can call
all they want. I'm deaf.
- Thanks. Mr Grey.
- Don't mention it. uh... Mr Green. right?
Right. Let's have your cab key. conductor.
I can't do that. I ain't supposed to do that.
You got three seconds
to live. conductor. One. two...
OK. OK. OK.
It'll mean my job.
What's he gonna do?
You wouldn't want me to spoil
the s-s-surprise. would you?
Until then. stay where you are.
Go back to normal speed when...
Command Centre callin' Pelham
One Two Three. Come in. please.
Sorry. I couldn't help it. It was automatic.
Pelham One Two Three. do you read me?
Come in. Pelham One Two Three.
Where the fuck are you?
Hey! What's the goddamn hurry?
I told you. one of my men dropped
his weddin' ring down the john!
- What are you runnin' for?
- Who's runnin'?
- How come that gate ain't locked?
- Who's gonna steal a subway train?
Grand Central Tower
callin' Command Centre.
Have you picked up on
Pelham One Two Three yet?
We're tryin' to find out.
- What'd he say?
- They're backed up all along the line.
Jesus Christ. Caz. you picked
a hell of a day to be late!
You wanted a plumber
down here. didn't ya?
- Whose goddamn weddin' ring was it?
- Mrs Jenkins'. But. Caz...
Sorry. Mr Dolowicz. It just slipped off.
- Why was your hand in the john anyway?
- My hand wasn't...
Go fish it out. would ya?
The toilet's behind the board.
Caz. listen to me! There's a train down!
Classification's been open
to a woman for only a month
and already we're in a goddamn toilet!
- What the hell's that?
- Marino's been tryin' to tell ya.
He's layin' down between 28th and 23rd.
- What the hell for? How long?
- Three minutes.
Command Centre's been tryin' to raise
him. but he don't answer his phone.
Jeez. Caz. why don't he answer his radio?
Maybe his radio's busted
and the son of a bitch is too lazy
to climb down and use the phone.
I'm gonna write him up for this!
I'm gonna have his ass!
Hey. it's movin'.
For Jesus Christ's sake.
the dumb bastard is movin' backwards.
Look. He left the front car behind.
The goddamn board must be busted.
He stopped again.
Well. stopped is better
than backwards at least.
What was that? I didn't know
these things went backwards.
Now you know.
Would you mind tellin' me
what you gentlemen are doing?
Yeah. I would.
Come in. Pelham One Two Three.
Come in.
- All right. Mr Green?
- Smooth as silk. Mr Blue.
- How do you feel?
- Great.
Get out. Doyle.
Here's your gun. Get going.
We're already two minutes late.
Pelham One Two Three.
Do you hear me. Pelham One Two Three?
Look. The front car's movin'.
And forward this time.
- I've got eyes. haven't I?
- What's goin' on down there?
Are you children with anybody?
You children... you with anybody?
Yeah. My mother.
Go back and join her.
- Why?
- Go back and join your mother.
Mom. we wanna play.
Your attention. please.
You'll all remain seated. Anybody
who tries to rise is going to get shot.
There's another one!
Shut up!
Move up a bit. Mr Doyle.
Ladies and gentlemen. you see this gun?
It fires 750 rounds of 9-millimetre
ammunition per minute.
In other words. if all of you
simultaneously were to rush me.
not a single one of you would get
any closer than you are right now.
Mom. are those real guns?
I do hope I have made myself understood.
He stopped again. The crazy dumb-ass
son of a bitch stopped again.
He's halfway between stations!
I'm gonna nail his pecker
to the goddamn wall for this.
- Caz. take it easy. will ya?
- Come on!
If I gotta watch my language because
they let a few broads in. I'm gonna quit!
How can you run a goddamn railroad
without swearin'?!
Grand Central Terminal.
who's in charge down there?
It's for you. Mr Dolowicz.
It's me. Frank. Caz Dolowicz.
We're watchin' it on the board.
Watchin' it?!
I got trains pilin' up behind it!
- Get some supervision down there!
- It's on its way. Frank.
I'll be back.
I've turned off the power.
Everybody in this part of the car.
move to the back.
Come on. Everybody in the front part
of the car move to the back.
- What the hell is goin' on?
- Move back. please. and sit down.
May I say something. please?
- Please. listen to me...
- Be quiet and sit down!
Let's go. honey.
All right. Mr Doyle.
What are you gonna do?
- What about this one?
- Let her sleep.
What you're going to do. Mr Doyle.
is to go back.
collect all the passengers
from the cars we've cut loose.
and walk them to 28th Street station.
- People hate to get off in a tunnel...
- Just do as you're told.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Can I go with him? I got
this very important appointment to see.
Nobody else leaves.
Aw. shit.
I'm sure you wouldn't mind
if the children were to go.
Sit down. madam. Didn't you hear
what I said? I said nobody else leaves.
Excuse me. mister. Don't you think
we should be let in on what's happening?
You're being held by four very dangerous
men armed with machine guns.
Ask a foolish question...
Be quiet.
Be quiet! Nothing will happen
as long as you obey my orders.
That's what they said in Vietnam.
and I still got my ass shot full of lead.
Shut your mouth. nigger!
- And keep it shut.
- Mr Grey!
It's terrible.
Who asked you to look?
All right. Mr Green?
The power's off at 14th Street and 33rd.
All four tracks. Local and express.
The north and the southbound.
Why am I still seeing lights?
That's emergency.
They run on AC like the signals.
Atchoo!
- Stop that. will you?
- Sorry.
Command Centre calling Pelham.
Did you cut off the power down there?
Without callin' to explain? Listen to me.
You've screwed up the
whole subway system.
Gentlemen. this is
the TA Command Centre.
A lot of laughs in here. Terrific place.
Each train is identified by the name of
its terminus and the time of its departure.
Thus an express train leavin' Woodlawn
at 6.30pm would be Woodlawn 6-3-0.
While on its return trip its destination
might be... let's say Flatbush 8-2-5.
- I hope you're memorisin' all this junk.
- Garber. what's the matter with you?
Don't worry.
They don't understand English.
This way. dummies.
Step this way. dummies.
Over here is Frank Correll. the Lord Byron
of the New York City Subway System.
Observe the way fire and smoke
shoot out of his ears.
Don't bug me. Garber. I got troubles here.
A train is down. its radio's dead.
the power's off. and it's dumped its load.
Aside from that. it's ginger-peachy.
What time is it. Mr Green?
Uh...
2.10.
Right. Time to talk to them.
- Is something troubling you?
- I think I'm gonna die today.
That's entirely possible.
This is Pelham One Two Three
to Command Centre.
This is Pelham One Two Three to
Command Centre. Do you read me?
OK. we'll leave him alone to his problems.
What are you tryin' to do?
Screw up this entire railroad?
- I want an explanation! It better be good!
- Your train has been taken.
- What?
- Repeat. your train has been taken.
Hey. shut up in here! Shut up!
I said shut it. everybody!
Shut it up. everybody. goddamnit!
The train has been taken?
- Are you the motorman?
- Negative.
Nobody's authorised to be in that cab
except the motorman. Identify yourself.
Your locomotive has been hijacked
by a group of heavily armed men.
It what?
We are holding 17 passengers and
the conductor hostage in the first car.
I am quite prepared to kill any
or all of them
if you do not obey my commands
to the letter.
- Have I made myself quite clear?
- You're outta your skull!
Be that as it may. get out a pen.
take down our list of demands.
Hey. now wait a minute.
Hold on. Stand by.
Why would anybody hijack
a goddamn subway train?
Hit your six button. Frank.
I want the TA police in on this.
What are all these Chinamen
doin' in here?
Holy Christ. I forgot.
Charlie. take these monkeys up to 13.
It is all right. Lieutenant Garber.
I am sure we can find it by ourselves.
Thank you for a most
instructive visit. Lieutenant.
A most exciting tour. Lieutenant.
Most exciting.
Garber to Patrone. Garber to Patrone.
Come in. Patrone.
This is Patrone.
Rico. I want you to plug everythin' you got
into the IRTtrain master's circuit.
And all units stand by on the double.
Call in the City cops. Put it on a 911
so their computer gets it.
What's up. Z?
- You won't believe it.
- I'll believe anythin'.
A train's been hijacked.
I don't believe it.
When did the power go?
- Conductor. when did the power go?
- Who wants to know?
Me! The supervisor of the Grand
Central Tower wants to know!
Oh. yes. sir! A couple of minutes ago!
Hey. what happened down there?
Who wants to know!
No. nobody's hurt!
- What's goin' on?
- I don't know what's goin' on!
- What happened?
- Nothin' happened. lady.
- Anybody killed?
- Nobody's killed.
On the left now. watch out for
the third rail. On the left now.
What the hell is this. for Christ's sake?
Your attention. please.
ladies and gentlemen.
I'm sure the more intelligent of you
have worked out you're all hostages.
Oh. my God!
Isn't that wonderful
- Hostages.
- What did you think? Guests?
When we get what we want.
you'll be released unharmed.
Until then. you'll continue to do
precisely as you're told.
Excuse me. sir. What's going to happen
to us if you don't get what you want?
Excuse me. sir. We are going
to get what we want.
I don't give a damn
what they were armed with.
They were gonna kill me!
You're like the captain of the ship!
You're supposed to go down with it!
- Horseshit!
- Oh. lady. butt out!
Tell Command Centre
I'll be on my way to investigate!
I wouldn't go
down there if I was you!
I know you wouldn't!
You work for the subway. mister? Tell 'em
I'm gonna sue! I'm gonna sue their ass off!
Pelham One Two Three
to Command Centre.
Are you ready to take down
our list of demands?
What do you want?
- Do you have your pen?
- Go on. for Pete's sake!
It's important you understand
three things.
1) Pelham One Two Three is
completely within our control.
2) We are all armed with
automatic weapons.
3) We have no scruples about killing.
- Do you understand me so far?
- I understand you fine. you lunatic.
Inform the mayor that we demand
one million dollars cash
for the release of the car
and all the hostages.
- That'll be the day.
- The time is now 2.13.
The money must be in our hands
not later than 3.13.
One hour from now.
If the money is not in our hands. we'll kill
one hostage for every minute you're late.
Keep dreamin'. maniac.
If anybody attempts to interfere
- anyone. in any way -
we will begin killing the hostages
immediately.
Confirm. please.
Zach! Zach!
- Pelham One Two Three. come in. please.
- This is Pelham.
Identify yourself. please.
This is Lieutenant Zachary Garber of the
Transit Police. Identify yourself. please.
I'm the man who stole your train.
Sir. there is no way you can get away with
this. You are underground in a tunnel.
Why concern yourself with that?
At precisely 3.13 we are going
to begin executing the hostages.
You'd better contact the mayor
and get back to me
for my further instructions.
Over and out.
Son of a bitch has got me backed up
all the way to the Bronx!
What is this. a circus?
Let's get back to work!
Rico. did you get that?
I only got your end of it.
but I could piece it together. It's crazy.
The guy's got a heavy English accent.
He could be a fruitcake.
We got anybody at 28th Street?
Just checkin' it out.
Yeah. he's around there somewhere.
Tell him to hold the fort. Could be
all day before the City cops show up.
They're never around when you need 'em.
Lex 28. Lex 28. Come in. please.
Patrolman James.
This is Lieutenant Patrone.
Where are you?
28th Street. southbound.
Look. Lieutenant. everything's cooled out.
Nothing's happenin'. What's goin' on?
Look. don't react to this.
but a train's been hijacked.
- Holy shit.
- For God's sake. don't say anythin'.
There's a supervisor from
Grand Central Tower.
Yeah. I saw him a few minutes ago.
He went down the track on foot.
Go after him.
See if you can turn him back.
Yes. sir.
All I know is I am the goddamn mayor
of the goddamn city of New York.
the second most important
elective office in the entire country.
and you tell me I gotta lay here and suffer
like every other schlub in the country?
I'm sorry you have the flu. Mr Mayor.
There's nothing more I can do.
There's one more thing. Get out!
You can't fight City Hall.
Yeah?
Al. it's Warren. I'm comin' upstairs.
I got a real bitch on our hands.
Don't tell me. I don't wanna know.
- I'm comin' up.
- Can't you handle it. Warren?
You are the goddamn
deputy mayor of the city of...
Sure I can handle it. Like I handle
every other filthy. stinkin' job
in this whole miserable city.
but I'm not gonna do it.
What is it? Another strike?
All right. all right.
I can take another strike.
A gang of men has hijacked
a subway train.
A gang of men...?
Has hijacked a subway train.
They want a million dollars for it.
Come on up.
Couple number one are the winners
of today's newlywed gamel
Missed it!
What do you want. Mr Green?
Is everythin' OK?
Go and sit down. I do not want Mr Grey
and Mr Brown alone with the passengers.
- Don't you trust them?
- I trust Mr Brown.
I do not trust Mr Grey.
I think that Mr Grey is an enormous
arrogant pain in the arse
who could turn out to be trouble.
I also think that he is mad.
Why do you think
they threw him out of the Mafia?
Ohh. terrific.
- Hold it right there. cowboy!
- Who are you?!
You'll find out
if you take another step!
I'm warnin' ya. mister! That's City
property you're foolin' around with!
That's just too fuckin' bad!
Why don't you go grab a goddamn
aeroplane like everybody else?
Cos we're afraid of flyin'!
Clear out or I'll shoot your ass off!
The hell with you! I'm comin' on board!
I warned you. stupid!
Holy shit!
I warned the bastard.
but he kept on comin' anyway.
- Was he alone?
- I didn't see nobody else.
Mr Brown.
I guess I got us on the scoreboard. right?
Take over from Mr Grey.
- A little quick with that gun.
- The jerk was comin' on board!
Loved every minute of it.
- Keep those children quiet.
- I'm trying! I can't!
- Do you want me to try?
- Oh. my God! No!
You said nobody was gonna get hurt.
Patrolman James callin' Operations.
This is Patrone.
Did you find that supervisor?
- He's dead. Lieutenant.
- Speak up. will ya? I can't hear ya.
I can't. I'm only 20 yards away
from the hijacked train.
They just shot him with a machine gun.
Is he dead?
- Wouldn't you be. Lieutenant?
- Stay put and keep an eye on things.
Z! They just drew first blood.
That supervisor from Grand Central
Tower. They just killed him.
Oh. my God. Thanks. Rico.
Frank. do you know who went
to 28th from Grand Central?
- Caz Dolowicz. Why?
- Jeez. I knew him.
Hey. whaddaya mean. you knew him?
They just shot him.
Dead?
- Caz? Fat Caz?
- Yeah.
- Garber?
- Aw. shit!
Garber? Are you there. Zach?
- Yeah. who is this?
- Costello.
Yes. Captain.
I'm puttin' you in charge at this end.
I'm goin' to headquarters.
If I don't show up.
the City cops'll hog all the action.
There's one on board the train.
One of the hostages.
You're kiddin'. A cop on the train?
How do you know?
There were two. but one got off at 33rd
and called in later when the news got out.
That means the other one's
still on the train.
- Plainclothes?
- Yeah. Tactical Force.
- Man or woman?
- I never even thought to ask.
Well. doesn't make any difference.
They can't do much single-handed.
Warren. I thought it over.
I know what we're gonna do.
Tell me.
We're gonna let 'em keep
the goddamn subway train.
We got plenty of them.
We'll never even miss it.
How about the 18 hostages?
We gonna miss them?
Warren. goddamnit!
This city hasn't got a million dollars!
Empty one of your Swiss bank accounts.
There's no other way out.
- Don't we get to think about it?
- There's no time.
I still want the full picture.
Get me the police commissioner.
the chairman of the Transit Authority.
and that putz we got for a comptroller.
They're on their way.
but it's no good runnin' to them. Al.
You're the mayor.
The buck stops with you.
- Oh. shit.
- God help us.
Shit! Piss! Fuck!
Call Charlie. Tell him
I'll get to him as soon as I can.
Where's that list on 144?
Command Centre callin'
Pelham One Two Three.
Frank. you're hoggin' my circuits.
I've got motormen callin' me from all over!
Tell 'em to get off the air.
I need some more lines open.
So talkin' to murderers takes priority
over runnin' a railroad?
My only priority is savin'
the lives of these passengers.
Screw the passengers! What do they
expect for 35 cents? To live for ever?
Oh. you're beautiful.
- Do you read me. Pelham?
- I'd go in with guns and blast 'em out!
Why don't you start doin' your work
and let the police do theirs. huh?
Like that cop on the train.
When's he gonna start shootin'?
We don't know if it is a "he".
- Do you read me. Pelham?
- Women cops! What good are they?
Probably can't find her gun
in her goddamn purse!
Pelham One Two Three.
Any news to report?
What's that about news?
Say again about news.
I said have you any news to report?
- No. nothin' yet.
- Atchoo!
Gesundheit!
- What are you calling about?
- Pelham. we need more time.
Shut the door. please.
It is 2.24. Lieutenant.
You've got 49 minutes left.
Be reasonable.
We're tryin' to cooperate.
but we can't do anything
if you don't give us enough time.
49 minutes.
We're dealin' with City Hall. You know
what a mess of red tape that is?
49 minutes.
Look. fella. we know how to tell the time.
but we aren't gonna get any place
if all you do is repeat 49 minutes!
48 minutes.
Yeah. all right. all right.
We'll get back to you as soon as we can.
To hear you plead with that chickenshit
makes me ashamed to be an American!
Go play with your trains.
Stay tuned for an update
on the subway hijacking case.
Get me the borough commander.
- Turn off that goddamn music.
- Yes. sir.
Harry? I'm headin' up to see the mayor.
What's it look like down there?
It's murder. Phil. as usual.
They really smell blood on this one.
- Who's your number two?
- Deputy Chief Inspector Daniels.
He's a good man. Phil.
He handled that protest last month.
- Get those photographers outta here!
- How are you deployed?
50 men inside the tunnel.
north and south of the train.
well concealed. all wearin' vests
and armed with machine guns.
shotguns. handguns. riot guns.
and a half-dozen snipers.
We could fight
the Third World War down there!
Make sure they stay outta sight. If the
hijackers see 'em. we'll have a massacre.
We have a sniper's report that
they're movin' around pretty freely.
The one in the motorman's cab
is an easy shot.
Absolutely no! Understand? We're takin'
the threat seriously! What's upstairs?
Trucks. cars. emergency and
medical units. The works. Phil.
Harry... tell me somethin'. will ya?
They're in a tunnel. surrounded on all
sides. How do they expect to get away?
Beats the shit out of me. Phil.
Oh. Al. it's disgustin'.
Would you stop it with the tissue?
Warren. tell him that other mayors have
to live in this house after we're gone.
Go on in there. Al. and I'll send
everybody in. Just sit down.
Thanks for comin' up
on such short notice. fellas.
You all know Jessie. don't you?
Good. Phil. just in time.
A little coffee? Some cake?
Better skip it. Jessie. We're short on time.
We know what's goin' on underground.
The issue is whether or not
we pay the ransom.
Phil? Whaddaya think?
Well. we're fully mobilised. There's
enough firepower to wipe out an army.
But... I can't guarantee
the safety of the hostages.
In other words. you're for
payin' the ransom.
Well. we don't want
another Attica. do we?
- So your vote is?
- I abstain.
Shit! Barney?
The safety of the passengers is
the only concern of the Transit Authority.
- Your vote?
- Pay the two dollars.
If it was two dollars.
I'd pay the two dollars. Barney!
It's a million! A one with six zeros!
Is it comin' outta your pocket?
Come on. will ya save the poor mouth
for later? How do you vote?
- I'm not through discussin' it yet.
- Yes. you are. Now vote.
My concern is with the taxpayers.
I always say millions for defence
but not one cent for tribute.
- Isn't that what I always say?
- Uh-huh. So that's a "no".
All right. Al. You've heard from
the Three Wise Men.
- Now what do you say?
- What are they goin' to say. Warren?
- Who?
- Everybody!
- The press! The man on the street!
- He means the voters.
The Times will support you.
the News will knock you.
The Post will take both sides. The rich'll
support you. Likewise the blacks.
The Puerto Ricans won't give a shit.
So quit stallin'.
Stop bullyin' everybody. Warren!
This is supposed to be a democracy!
Wise up. for Christ sake! We're tryin' to
run a city. not a goddamn democracy!
Al. quit fartin' around! We've gotta pay!
Jessie?
Jessie. what do you say?
A million dollars sounds like
a lot of money.
But just think what
you're gonna get in return.
- What?
- 18 sure votes.
All right. All right. Warren?
- Warren. arrange for the payoff.
- Hallelujah.
Fellas. you heard him. Phil. pass the word
to the bad guys that we're coughin' up.
- What bank do we do business with?
- City National Trust. I'll call.
I'll call. You'll take an hour tryin'
to knock down the interest rate.
Jessie?
I think I handled it all right.
A regular Fiorello La Guardia.
- Patrolman James callin' Operations.
- This is Patrone. What's goin' on?
There's a lot of feet movin' around
out here in the dark.
I figure it's a couple of dozen
sharpshooters and snipers.
- Am I right?
- I wouldn't be surprised.
Make sure they know I'm standin' here
between them and the hijackers.
I'm not all that easy to see in the dark.
Nothin' yet?
Boy! They're sure takin'
their time. aren't they?
- Don't worry. They're gonna have to pay.
- Suppose they don't?
Well. then a lot of people are gonna die.
Includin' us.
Better than selling life insurance. isn't it?
Life insurance? You told me
you were in the army.
I was. That's where I developed
my expensive tastes.
British army. $ 150 a month.
You gotta be kiddin'.
The Africans paid me 5.000.
- A month?
- For leading a battalion.
Jesus! What the hell'd
you get outta that for?
Because the market dried up.
Wow!
5.000!
At least you weren't fired.
But I don't give a shit.
What guy wants to drive a subway train
for the rest of his life?
What did they catch you doing?
Nothin'.
I mean. they framed me.
They needed a fall guy.
Transit cops. Undercover guys.
They got wind of a gang passin' dope.
Transportin' from downtown to uptown.
and givin' it to a motorman.
They tried to pin the evidence on me.
but they didn't find a thing.
You were innocent?
Of course I was innocent.
You think I'd do a thing like that?
I'm on my way to headquarters.
We got the green light.
That's great news.
The men are rarin' to go.
No! We're paying 'em the ransom money.
Pass the word along to the hijackers.
Roger.
Borough Command to the 28th Street
platform. Come in. Daniels.
Daniels.
The mayor's agreed to pay.
Let the hijackers know right away.
Roger.
Command Centre. this is 28th Street.
Do you read me. Command Centre?
- This is Command Centre. Who is this?
- Chief Inspector Daniels.
The mayor's agreed to pay.
Pass it on to the hijackers right away.
Will do. sir.
Pelham One Two Three.
Come in. Pelham One Two Three.
This is Pelham One Two Three.
I read you.
We agree to pay the ransom.
Repeat. we agree to pay...
What? They're gonna do what?
Do you read me. Pelham One Two Three?
- Zach. you're outta your skull.
- I read you. Garber.
Take down my next instructions.
to be followed to the letter.
The money's to be paid
in the following denominations.
500.000 dollars in fifties.
500.000 dollars in hundreds. Right?
500.000 in fifties. 500.000 in hundreds.
Which will be put
in stacks of 200 bills each.
bound with two thick elastic bands.
Two stacks of bills. bound in what?
Bound with thick elastic bands.
All of the bills will be old bills.
their serial numbers to be random.
Now that's all. When the delivery arrives
we'll contact you with further instructions.
- About what? Your getaway?
- Signing off now.
Son of a bitch!
Hey. Pelham. It might interest you to
know I figured out how you're gonna do it.
Yes. it would interest me very much.
You're gonna make everyone
in New York City
close their eyes and count
to a hundred. right?
It is now 2.47. That means
you have got 26 minutes...
Hey. wait a minute. pal. We agreed
to pay the money. Turn your clock off!
- 26 minutes.
- Your instructions were complicated.
The money has to be counted.
stacked. transported.
It just isn't physically possible.
You'd be surprised
what's physically possible.
The clock's running.
26 minutes. After that.
we scratch 'em off one per minute.
Your attention. please!
Ladies and gentlemen.
it might interest you to know
the city of New York has agreed
to pay for your release.
As soon as the money gets here.
will you let us go?
Soon after.
Excuse me. sir. Would you mind
telling us how much you're getting?
- Why is that of interest to you. sir?
- Well. a person likes to know his worth.
- One million dollars.
- That's not so terrific.
FEDERAL RESERVE BANK OF NEW YORK
LOWER MANHATTAN
Pull your pants up. Al.
We're goin' downtown.
- Totally out of the question. Mr LaSalle.
- Nobody asked you.
Warren. for Pete's sake.
I'm sick as a goat. What's the point?
The point. for Pete's sake. is that
the mayor of the city of New York.
trailin' by 22 points in all the polls.
cares enough about
18 citizens in jeopardy
to make a personal appearance
in their behalf.
You know what'll happen?
What always happens. I'll get booed.
- He's a very sick man.
- Will you let go of that!
All you have to do is say a few words
to the hijackers over a bullhorn.
You make a dignified plea for mercy.
Warren. suppose the hijackers
start shootin' at me?
Will you stop!
They have no reason to shoot at you.
Why? Do you think
they're from outta town?
Get dressed. Al. I'll do the jokes.
Garber. Come in. Garber.
Come in. Garber.
- Who are we waitin' for. Z?
- Beats me.
How long's it take to get
all that money together?
We'll never make it.
The passengers are dead ducks.
- I wonder what that cop's thinkin'.
- What cop?
The one who's a hostage.
Shit. I'm glad it's not me.
- Where's that money?
- Make yourself useful.
Get Personnel to get a list of all motormen
discharged durin' the past ten years.
- What are you lookin' for?
- Somebody down there can drive a train.
Tell 'em you want it today.
Mr Grey. can I have a word
with you. please?
Will you stop messing around
with that girl. Mr Grey?
She's a 20-buck-a-trick hooker.
- Who's a 20-buck-a-trick hooker?
- Leave her alone.
Who are you to go around
callin' people "hooker"?!
I can do this job and hump
that broad at the same time.
Listen. you little prick! 20 bucks
wouldn't buy you a good-night kiss!
I'm giving you an order. Mr Grey.
Blow it outta your ass.
Colonel.
You're talkin' to the wrong man.
I'm not your Mr B-B-B-Brown.
I once had a man shot
for talking to me like that.
Well. that's the difference between us.
I've always done my own killin'.
Takin' a hell of a long time.
Think how many times you gotta wet
your thumb to count a million bucks.
Command Centre callin' 28th Street.
Come in. Inspector.
This is Daniels.
- Has the money left yet. Inspector?
- Not yet.
What are they waitin' for?
Give 'em a goose. will ya?
We're runnin' outta time!
Pelham One Two Three. this is Command
Centre. Come in. Pelham One Two Three.
- This is Pelham One Two Three.
- This is Garber.
We're movin' a little slowly at this end.
Pelham. We need some more time.
Sorry. no more time.
If you can just see your way...
- Will you hold it down. Frank?
- I want a local sent around the loop...
I said knock it off!
I'm tryin' to buy some time here!
And I'm tryin' to run a railroad!
While you're playin' grab-ass
with a bunch of pirates!
How about 15 more minutes. Pelham?
A lousy 15 minutes?
Negative.
Ten minutes. then. What difference
can ten minutes make to you?
Negative.
- Anythin' wrong?
- Wanted more time.
- How much more?
- Just ten minutes.
- That can't hurt anybody.
- I didn't give it to them.
- Suppose they can't make it?
- Then we do what we said we'd do.
- Maybe an hour isn't enough time.
- You give 'em an hour. they take an hour.
Give 'em two hours. they take two hours.
An hour is plenty of time. Mr Green.
Yeah. but supposin' it isn't?
This is the borough commander.
Come in. Headquarters Charlie!
Aren't you guys movin' yet?
Do you know what the damn time is?
We're still waitin' for the money. sir.
If I don't see your faces before the
deadline. I don't wanna see them at all!
- Everl
- Yes. sir.
I told you. It's gonna be our ass.
- This is a million dollars?
- It's what it buys. Not what it weighs.
Eight minutes. We're not gonna make it.
- Inspector. where are they now. please?
- Centre Street. just north of Chambers.
That gives us seven minutes.
Not enough time. sir.
Even if they get to 28th Street on time.
we still gotta carry it down track on foot.
No way. sir.
Look. we're scarin' the shit
outta everybody.
Yeah. includin' me.
Pelham One Two Three. this is Garber.
Come in. Pelham One Two Three.
Garber. this is Pelham One Two Three.
The money's en route. makin' pretty good
time too. but it won't get to you by 3.13.
I'm very sorry to hear that.
Suppose we get it to the entrance by then.
Will you change your deadline from
delivery to you to arrival at 28th Street?
Would you do that at least? Do you
read me. Pelham. for cryin' out loud?
All right. Garber.
But no more concessions.
- Is that quite clear?
- Quite clear. Quite clear.
They bought it. If we get the money
to the station by 3.13 we'll be OK.
Good work. Garber.
Headquarters Charlie.
headin' north on Centre Street...
You've got four minutes!
Yes. sir. we'll make it...
We'll never make it.
Sir. the mayor is on his way down.
We'll hold the crowd till he gets here.
Mr Green.
Yes.
Coming up in one minute.
Have you decided which one
it's gonna be?
Does that make any difference?
I guess not.
OK. 50 seconds and then
I'm gonna eliminate one.
Headquarters Charlie.
approachin' Astor Place.
You've still got 28 blocks!
Floor the son of a bitch!
Whaddaya mean. it's been wrecked?
We're outta time!
I know we're outta time.
Couldn't make it. that's all.
That's all? They're about
to shoot an innocent person!
If they know the truck is wrecked.
how can they expect us to be on time?
They don't know anythin' down there.
How can they know anythin'...
Holy mackerel. that's it.
Pelham One Two Three. the money has
arrived. Repeat. the money has arrived.
Do you read me. Pelham One Two Three?
The money has arrived.
This is Pelham One Two Three.
You made it just in time. didn't you?
Get it up there! Move!
I hope it works.
Are you still there. Garber?
Still here. Tell me somethin'. Pelham.
If we were a second late. you would've
knocked off an innocent party?
Affirmative. Now the instructions
for the delivery of the money.
As usual. you'll follow them
to the letter. OK?
I got it. Go ahead.
Two unarmed policemen...
Atchoo!
Gesundheit.
Two unarmed policemen
will walk down the track.
One with the money.
the other with a torch.
which he will flash continuously
from side to side.
When they reach the car.
the rear door will be opened
and the one with the money
will throw it onto the train.
Then they will both turn and walk back
to 28th Street station. Acknowledge.
- I got it. Is that all?
- That's all for now.
But keep in mind. won't you.
that the same ground rules apply.
Any wrong move by anyone
and I kill a hostage.
Coulda guessed that part.
You have got five minutes
to deliver this money.
You don't think
you're gonna get out. do ya?
It's now 3.14.
You've got till 3.19.
Over.
Over. Bastard.
About fuckin' time!
You two! Get the money outta there!
Which one has the flashlight?
Then you carry the money.
Gimme that paper.
You've got four minutes!
Never mind the goddamn salutes!
Just get goin'!
Jesus. it's the goddamn mayor.
- You get the feelin' we ain't alone?
- Whaddaya mean?
We got four sub-machine-guns in front
of us. and all these jokers behind us.
I feel like I'm walkin' into
the fuckin' OK Corral.
Pow!
Shit!
Hold your fire. goddamnit!
Quiet!
- Are you all right?
- Yeah. It's not too b-b-bad.
- I think it went right through.
- Move back. come on. Move back.
Give me that scarf. Give me that scarf!
Keep quiet!
- OK?
- Yeah. I don't feel p-pain too much.
- How many shots?
- Just one.
The rest was me and then they answered.
I didn't see anybody. I just got mad.
Goddamnit!
Mr Grey?
You don't think they're finished
out there. do ya?
Go back there and help Mr Green.
will you. please?
Some girl-scout
chickenshit outfit I'm in here.
I suppose somebody out there
got nervous or bored.
Been there a long time.
Can't afford to let it pass.
Who started it?
Who fired first? Them or us?
I don't know. Lieutenant. It came from
somewhere behind me in the dark.
It had to be one of the snipers.
Somebody just took it in his head
to fire on his own? How could he?
Easy. Lieutenant.
Real easy.
Can you see what's goin' on
inside the train?
No. not too good.
I'd sure hate to be in there findin' out.
Conductor.
- You mean me?
- Yes. Stand up and come down here.
- Why. what are you gonna do?
- You can help me.
- Come on. Come down here.
- Look. if he doesn't wanna go...
All right. everybody. Just get back
on your seats. Very quietly.
Come on. Back on your seats.
All right. conductor. I want you to
walk up track about a hundred feet.
Just wait for the men delivering
the money. all right?
I'll open the door for you.
Why do I have to go?
Come on. Please go.
There's nothing to worry about.
Look! Somebody's climbin' down!
Christ. he's comin' this way!
Oh. no!
What?
Why would they shoot a hostage?
We're still under the deadline.
- Somebody threw a shot at them.
- Who the hell was it?
Nobody knows. My bet is we never will.
Z. when are we gonna hear
from that cop who's on board?
What do you want. Rico? A suicide?
There's heavily armed men down there.
What chance has one lousy cop got.
especially if it's a dame?
Boy. what a mess!
Pelham One Two Three. come in.
This is Garber.
Here is Pelham One Two Three.
Come in. Garber.
For Christ's sake. fella.
did ya have to do it?
One of my men was fired at.
I warned you what the penalty would be.
- Yeah. you warned me.
- Where's the money?
I'm going to give you 30 seconds more.
Hey. you guys!
- Christ. who's that?
- Transit cop. I got orders for you.
Resume delivery on the double.
I don't suppose we could
have that in writin'?
Mr Blue. we got a light!
All right. Open the door.
would you. Mr Brown?
All right. gentlemen.
Hands in evidence. please.
Put up your hands!
All right. Throw the money up here.
Into the cab.
Push it up.
Thank you. Now turn around.
Go home to your wives and children.
Keep the hands up. Take it very easily.
Shut the door. Mr Brown. will you?
Mr Grey.
Jesus H Christ!
I've never seen a million dollars before.
You can load up first. Mr Grey.
I'll talk to Garber.
All that money! I can't believe it!
I'm gonna die today.
Well... either you live or you die.
- That's 18 packs each. right?
- Right.
This is Pelham One Two Three.
Do you read me. Garber?
- This is Garber. Go ahead.
- I'm gonna give you three instructions.
Each one is to be followed precisely.
Is that clear?
So far.
1) At the end of this conversation. you
will restore power to the entire sector.
Right. Restore power.
2) You will clear the local track all the
way from 28th Street to South Ferry.
By clear I mean switches properly set.
all signals green.
I emphasise green. Garber.
If I so much as see a red light.
let alone get tripped by one.
I'll shoot another hostage.
You will also remove all police
from the tunnel.
If I see a policeman
between here and South Ferry.
I'll shoot another hostage.
Any deviation. I'll shoot another hostage.
Listen. fella. after this is over
you should seek out psychiatric help.
Let me know when all my points have
been complied with. Over and out.
- Rico. are you there?
- I'm here. Z. What's up?
Hold on while I cut in the City cops.
Frank. hook me up and get outta there.
What a way to run a railroad!
- Inspector Daniels. This is Garber.
- This is Daniels.
Inspector. I have Lieutenant Patrone
of the Transit Police on the line.
The hijackers want power restored.
all tracks cleared.
signals green to South Ferry.
and no cops anywhere in sight.
OK. sir. so we go along with that.
We have to. But then what?
- What do you think they got in mind?
- Beats me. Z.
I wouldn't have picked a tunnel
for a getaway.
But they did pick it.
And since everythin' they've done has
been worked out to the smallest detail.
it stands to reason
they got the rest worked out.
Power restored and track cleared.
But why South Ferry?
Well. do you think it's the water. Rico?
Maybe they got a boat in the harbour.
We'd better play it one step at a time.
Garber. you see about restorin' the power.
I'll start pullin' our units out of the tunnel.
We can follow them on the street.
Except how do we know where they'll be?
Grand Central Tower
has 'em on their board.
They stop any place before South Ferry.
we know about it.
I'll check in when I get to my car.
I just figured out how
they're gonna get away.
- I'm listenin'.
- They're gonna fly the train to Cuba.
You're a sick man. Rico.
Whaddaya want me to do?
The power's still off! Move 'em by bus!
You haven't got any buses?
Go out and hijack some!
Hey. Garber. what's goin' on?
Do I get my trains back now or don't I?
You don't. Not yet.
Do you realise the goddamn
rush hour starts in an hour?
Will you shut up and listen?
I got a new set of instructions.
Your fuckin' instructions! I'm not liftin' a
finger to help the killers of Caz Dolowicz.
Hey!
Now you listen to me.
you dumb son of a bitch.
If you don't do what I say. you'll be havin'
dinner tonight with Caz Dolowicz!
Jesus Christ. what are you...!
OK.
Better take the case out.
All right. ladies and gentlemen.
Pay attention. please.
In a while we hope to be moving again.
Then. with a bit of luck.
you'll be released unharmed.
Until then. of course.
you'll continue to obey my orders.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Hey. dude.
As you're goin' downtown anyway. you
mind droppin' me off at Fulton Street?
You're a wise mother. you know that?
Like some more?
This'll give 'em a jolt.
even before they expected it.
- Look at this.
- Holy Christ. she's movin'.
They promised to wait until
we cleared track all the way down.
Jenkins. get Command Centre.
Grand Central Tower.
callin' Command Centre.
- Command Centre.
- She's movin'.
- Who's movin'?
- Pelham One Two Three.
What? Since when?
Just started.
Hold on. I'll put ya on a tie-in.
Rico. she's movin'.
- Who's movin'?
- Who do ya think? Pelham.
- It's too soon. We're not set up yet.
- You heard from Daniels yet?
He's in a squad car
on Park Avenue South.
- Inspector? She's movin'. sir.
- Who's movin'?
What's the matter with everybody?
How many hijacked trains we got?
They're not supposed to do that yet.
How far have they gone?
- Grand Central? How far have they gone?
- Comin' up on 23rd Street.
- Better move those cops off the platform.
- Better follow along down Park Avenue.
Get me 23rd Street.
Comin' in to 23rd Street.
All right. Steady as she goes now.
Garber? Just had a terrible thought. What
if they set the throttle and jumped off?
While we're chasin' the train. they're
sneakin' out somewhere behind us.
Ingenious. sir. except it's impossible.
- Why?
- A gizmo known as a deadman's feature.
It's built into the control handle
in case the motorman drops dead.
The handle has to have a man's hand
pressin' down on it. hard. at all times.
Otherwise it don't work.
The train stops cold.
I see.
Nice try. though. I'll give 'em a call
in case you're still worried about it.
Pelham One Two Three.
what's goin' on down there?
The tracks aren't cleared yet.
How come you're movin'?
We're trying to put some
distance between us
and all those policemen
you've got hidden back there.
You're gonna run into a lot of red signals.
- I don't want you to blame us for it.
- I won't blame you for anything.
Just let us know when you've
cleared the track. OK. signing off.
Do you think he's able to figure anythin'
out? I mean. all those questions.
Not surprising under
the circumstances. is it?
They're thinking what
we want them to think.
Ah. there it is.
OK. Stop a few yards past it. will you?
All right.
Thank you. Mr Green.
He shut down again. Pass it along.
Grand Central Tower callin' Command
Centre. Come in. Command Centre.
Command Centre.
She stopped again. Lieutenant.
Below 18th Street station.
Got ya. Thanks.
Inspector. they stopped again.
Where are you?
- Approachin' 17th Street.
- Pull over. You're right above them.
And then what?
It's up to them. I'll get back to you. sir.
Pelham One Two Three. Callin' Pelham
One Two Three. Come in. please.
Pelham One Two Three. Pelham One Two
Three. this is Command Centre. Come in.
Quick as you can.
Pelham One Two Three.
This is Garber. Come in. please.
Come in. please.
What the hell's goin' on out there?
Who s-s-said you could talk?
Pelham One Two Three. come in. Pelham
One Two Three. why don't you answer?
Frank. how long before
the track's cleared?
You mean before this railroad is so fucked
it'll take a computer to put it back?
Yes. Frank. that's what I meant.
About five or six minutes.
I got a snag at Brooklyn Bridge.
- There's somethin' goin' on down there.
- Whaddaya think?
I don't have the slightest idea.
Rico. I don't care what those clowns said.
I want men on every...
Wait a minute. Hold on a second.
Inspector Daniels?
I think we need officers on every platform
from 14th Street to South Ferry.
Good idea. Lieutenant. Will do.
I'll come up to 17th Street and join ya.
Rico. how about that list of motormen?
They're workin' on it. I told 'em to rush it.
Come up here and take over the radio for
me. But don't tell 'em the track's clear.
I don't want them startin' again
until I get there.
Will do. Z.
- Inspector Daniels?
- Daniels.
Oh. l. uh... I thought you were a. uh...
like a shorter guy.
I don't know what I thought.
- Anythin' happenin'?
- They're still down there.
If this street collapsed.
we'd land right on top of 'em.
Command Centre to DCl. Manhattan.
Yeah. Rico. this is Garber.
Track's been cleared for two minutes.
Should I call the hijackers?
Yeah. let 'em know. And let us know
when they start movin'. will ya?
What do we do? If they pick up speed
on us we'll have trouble keepin' up.
I think we oughta take off.
Get a jump on them for a change.
Move it. Tell the sergeant to hold
the men here until further word.
Yes. sir.
Fits like a glove.
- Is it gonna come away clean?
- It's gonna work all right.
Command Centre to
Pelham One Two Three.
- Who's that?
- Give me the mike.
- Here.
- This is Pelham.
- What happened to Garber?
- Even great men have to pee.
The track's cleared
all the way to South Ferry.
Thank you.
Give the lieutenant my regards.
- Do it yourself. at the arraignment.
- Over and out.
Best get going.
All right. Mr Brown.
You will all remain seated.
That means nobody is to get up.
OK.
- Now what?
- Me you're askin'?
OK. Come on.
Hey. where are you goin'?!
I'm a police officer!
- Mr Blue?
- Yeah. what do you want?
- I thought I saw somethin' f-f-fall off.
- What do you mean. something?
- Might've been a person. I ain't sure.
- All right. let's make sure.
We haven't got time.
Get back up here. Come on.
Command Centre.
Pelham One Two Three's in motion!
Where do you think
they're takin' us now?!
- Don't worry. they're gonna let us all go!
- How do you know that?!
They got the money!
They got what they want!
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
Can't anybody count?
They all four got off!
There's nobody drivin' the fuckin' train!
Anybody in there?!
All right. all clear.
All right. then. You know the drill.
We do it by the numbers. Hats.
- Glasses.
- Drills and numbers...
This is all chickenshit.
Why don't we just do it?
Moustaches.
All right. reverse coats.
Pelham One Two Three's between Astor
Place and Bleecker. Speed's increasin'.
Pelham One Two Three now between
Astor Place and Bleecker.
Doesn't make any sense. They know
we're monitorin' their position.
- So?
- So it's dumb.
Who said crooks were smart?
But these have been smart.
We're overlookin' somethin'. Inspector.
OK. New hats.
OK. Magazines in pockets.
- I never knew these things went so fast!
- We're gonna be killed!
- Stop it! Nobody's gonna get killed!
- A hell of a lot you know. old man!
But I do know! I've been ridin' the
subways since before you were born!
I'm an expert. You see. they have
something called stoppers.
or stickers. or something like that.
And whenever a train goes by a red light.
these things stop them.
- There's just one thing. baby!
- What's that?
They're all green!
Inspector. that short move they made
between 28th Street and 17th Street.
- Why'd they do that?
- I don't know.
Suppose they wanted to do somethin'
they didn't want anybody else
to know about?
- Like what?
- Like jumpin' off the train.
Turn around.
We're goin' back to 17th Street.
- Like hell we are!
- They are not on the train. I'm sure of it.
I suggested that in the first place.
You shot me down.
- A deadman's feature?
- They figured out how to beat that!
That's their plan!
That's what they started with!
Turn this thing around and burn rubber.
Guns to Mr Brown.
Mr Grey. would you be good enough
to give that gun to Mr Brown. please?
No. This ain't gonna go nowhere.
This is gonna stay with me.
Mr Grey. bring that gun back here. please.
What if they're waitin' for us up there?
I want some heavy artillery with me.
- Mr Grey. I won't ask you again.
- Blow it outta your ass. Mr Blue.
Oh. my God.
Let's get his money!
Mr Green. come on!
Mr Blue!
Did you get him?
You go on ahead. We'll meet
where we planned. Right?
- You better be right about this. Garber.
- Even if I am. it's probably too late.
Where are those goddamn red lights?!
We're not stopping!
There is going to be a red light!
There has to be!
- What if there isn't?!
- There has to be!
Check the emergency exits!
Inspector. you take 15th Street.
Officer. you take 17th Street.
Right. sir.
Are you a policeman?
Well done. The mayor
will go to your funeral.
Excuse me. fella.
would you mind droppin' that gun?
Drop it!
Officer. I suppose you couldn't use
a quarter of a million dollars. could you?
Quarter of a million? No. thanks.
My accountant says I've accepted
enough for this fiscal quarter.
You're the English guy on the radio.
Yes.
- Lieutenant Garber?
- Right. Do you wanna move along?
Excuse me... Do you people
still execute in this state?
What? Oh. execute.
No. Not at the moment.
Pity.
Christ!
We'll have an ambulance here in no time.
miss. Everything's gonna be OK.
Where are those goddamn red lights?!
Oh. God!
Stop!
There has to be.
It's headin' to the South Ferry loop!
It must be goin' about 70mph!
My God! Look!
We'll never make it!
I told you it would stop. Didn't I?
42nd Street already?
Get that list out on the wire.
Tell 'em it's top priority.
Whaddaya got. Rico?
We got positive identification
on the three dead men. Here.
George Steever. Professional guy. huh?
- St Louis.
- Yeah. I know how to read. Rico.
Giuseppe Benvenuto.
alias - heh-heh - Joe Welcome.
- Where's the guy who fried himself?
- No card on him.
We got a confirm on his prints
from Immigration.
Name's Bernard Ryder. Mercenary
soldier. Between wars. I guess.
None of these guys know how to drive
a train. It's the motorman who's missin'.
Did you get that list of motormen
who were discharged?
Yeah. 78 names.
78?
Yeah. but it's not that bad.
Eight are dead. 22 were rehired.
11 are in jail.
26 moved away.
One's in a mental institution. Another
is a member of the Police Department.
That's our man right there.
Sorry to disappoint you. Zachary.
but he was accounted for.
- So how many does that leave?
- Only nine.
Only nine. All right. let's get goin'.
What's the name of this guy?
Nathaniel Muscat.
- What'd he get busted for?
- Narcotics.
This way.
- Who's there?
- Transit Police.
Just a minute.
What do you want?
Uh. nothin'. fella. Our mistake.
A spokesman for the Transit Authority
noted that the subway car
carrying the hostages
was stopped at the South Ferry loop
by the automatic safety features
which are activated by any car
travelling at excessive speed.
- Transit Authority.
- Still gotta pay.
- Your name is Latimer?
- What about it?
Just answer the question. would ya?
I don't work for you guys any more.
You don't get shit from me.
Can you account for your
whereabouts today. Mr Latimer?
Are you tryin' to connect me
to that hijackin'? Forget it!
I've been here since 2.30 this afternoon.
- Are you sure?
- Sure? Ask anybody!
- Don't worry. we will.
- Hold it!
It's still gonna be 50 cents.
- Who's that?
- Police Department.
- Who?
- Harold Longman. it's the Transit Police.
Oh. Jesus!
Wait a minute!
Just a minute!
- How many more we gotta see today?
- Six. seven. I don't know.
Come on. Mr Longman.
we ain't got all night!
I'll be right out!
I hope he washes his hands
before he opens the door.
- Yes. what is it?
- Harold Longman?
- We'd like to ask a couple of questions.
- What about?
- Will you let us in?
- We'll just take one minute of your time.
I'm Lieutenant Patrone.
This is Lieutenant Garber.
I'm sorry to bother you like this.
- Nice place you got here. Mr Longman.
- Thanks.
Can you give us an account of
your whereabouts this afternoon?
Why?
- Were you at work?
- No.
- Why not?
- I work nights.
- Where do you work?
- Kennedy Airport.
- What do you do over there?
- I'm a... fork-lift operator.
I got a brother-in-law does that
over in Jersey.
That's interestin' work.
Where were you this afternoon.
Mr Longman?
- Why?
- You tell me where. I'll tell you why.
I was. uh... right here.
Can anyone verify that fact?
You said you'd tell me why.
- You were here all afternoon?
- I sleep in the afternoon.
- All afternoon?
- Well... till about an hour ago.
- But you heard about the hijackin'?
- What hijackin'?
- The subway train.
- Subway...!
- You gotta be kiddin'!
- Do I look like I'm kiddin'?
I mean. would I be here
if I was kiddin'. mister?
Subway...! Who'd wanna
do a thing like that?
- Hey. Z. You got a match?
- No.
- You got a warrant?
Supreme Court says you have to have
a warrant. unless I'm under arrest.
The way things are goin'. they're gonna
be changin' that in about 10 minutes.
- Mr Longman. you got a match?
- No.
That's all right. I'll get it at the stove.
I'll get it.
It's a little tricky.
Has a tendency to explode.
Rico. let's go.
Thanks. Mr Longman.
Mr Longman. we'll be back later.
Yeah? Listen. I know I got a gripe
with the TA. I know I got a bum rap.
But I wouldn't do anythin' as stupid
as what you just told me.
What do think I am? A jerk? Do me a
favour. will ya? Get the hell outta here.
Come on. Mr Longman. We have
to follow our leads. It's our job!
Yeah. yeah. Big deal.
Look. I got my rights. This is my home.
I want a little peace!
Just do me a favour.
Get the hell outta here.
Sorry if we bothered ya. Mr Longman.
Come on. Rico.
- Atchoo!
- Gesundheit!
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-